<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ReaL</title>
    <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://real.fahimsikder.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ReaL</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://real.fahimsikder.com/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>ReaL</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Event</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/event/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/event/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including page elements such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair Generative Models</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/project/fair-generative-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 23:01:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/project/fair-generative-models/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TruestLLM</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/project/my-project-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 22:53:03 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/project/my-project-name/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Sparse Gaussian Process Regression for Trajectory Modeling</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-online-nodate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 22:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-online-nodate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian optimization for selecting training and validation data for supervised machine learning</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/bergstrom-bayesian-nodate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 22:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/bergstrom-bayesian-nodate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Unsupervised Learning, Classiﬁcation and Prediction of Activities in a Stream-Based Framework</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-towards-nodate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 22:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-towards-nodate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WASP ED to make Swedish universities leading in AI</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/post/wasp-ed-to-make/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 23:56:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/post/wasp-ed-to-make/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-revolution&#34;&gt;AI revolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of research, artificial intelligence is often described as the new industrial revolution. It covers everything from voice control and computer vision to robots working together, self-driving cars, advanced visualisation and interaction, and more. LiU has for several years been host to a number of AI-related research projects, including the research programme WASP, which stands for Wallenberg AI, Autonomous Systems and Software Program. The programme is the biggest ever of its kind in Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2021, it was announced that W TMS Therapy is ‘Promising’ for Alcohol Treatment ASP, together with its humanities and social sciences-focussed sister programme WASP-HS, had received funds worth SEK 18.6 million from the Marcus and Marianne Wallenberg Foundation. The funds are to be used to start WASP-ED. The aim of WASP-ED is to significantly increase the ability and capacity of Swedish universities to provide modern and relevant education in AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fredrik Heintz, professor at LiU, is one of Sweden’s most prominent AI researchers, and is in charge of WASP-ED. This is what he said about the new funding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now we can work on a national level with educational questions related to AI and other transformative technologies. Our goal is to support all education – not just technical education – in taking a significant, qualitative step forward in their work with AI and what we call transformative technologies.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweden’s broadest range of AI courses is at LiU</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/post/sweden-broadest-range-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 23:53:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/post/sweden-broadest-range-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fredrik Heintz is one of Sweden’s leading AI researchers. He is also extremely active in spreading knowledge about artificial intelligence to the general public, where one of his initiatives is his introductory course in AI: “Grunderna i AI”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everybody’s talking about AI, but not many people really understand what it’s about. There’s an obvious knowledge gap. AI already affects large parts of society, and its effects will probably increase”, says Fredrik Heintz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of the application of AI that are already commonplace are voice control, machine translation, and internet search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There’s a lot of hype around AI at the moment, so it’s important to have a fundamental understanding of what artificial intelligence is. It’s not a case of understanding all of the details, but having an insight into how the underlying technology affects us. How does machine learning work? How can a computer learn from examples? In order to understand how filter bubbles arise, we should know how algorithm-controlled information flows work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who want to learn more, and may even be aiming for a career in artificial intelligence, Linköping University offers Sweden’s broadest range of courses in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We cover the complete range from mathematical and theoretical AI to the combination of hardware and software, and, of course, courses focussed on computer science. Since the students have access to the complete range of courses, they can choose anything that suits them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any particular programmes that you recommend for people who want to work in artificial intelligence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Right from the start, when Linköping University decided to offer courses and programmes in computer science around 1980, AI was an important part. We have a long and unique tradition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our Master’s programme in computer science and software engineering includes AI as part of the core curriculum. I’m convinced that it is one of the best programmes if you want to approach AI from a computer science perspective. Other suitable programmes are the Master’s programmes in computer science &amp;amp; engineering and in applied physics &amp;amp; electrical engineering. But you must remember that our broad offering of courses in AI is available for everyone taking our programmes.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Lattice-based Motion Planning with Introspective Learning and Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-enhancing-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-enhancing-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incremental reasoning in probabilistic Signal Temporal Logic</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-incremental-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-incremental-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Autonomous Exploration Planning of Large-Scale 3-D Environments</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/selin-efficient-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/selin-efficient-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Receding-Horizon Lattice-Based Motion Planning with Dynamic Obstacle Avoidance</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/andersson-receding-horizon-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/andersson-receding-horizon-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Process Based Motion Pattern Recognition with Sequential Local Models</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-gaussian-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-gaussian-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream Reasoning Using Temporal Logic and Predictive Probabilistic State Models</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-stream-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/tiger-stream-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards learning and classifying spatio-temporal activities in a stream processing framework</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/endriss-towards-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/publication/endriss-towards-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/people/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour</title>
      <link>https://real.fahimsikder.com/tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://real.fahimsikder.com/tour/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
